<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-25T19:49:29-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Iguape - Paineira Graphical User Interface</title><subtitle>Iguape is the Paineira Graphical User Interface, a UI designed for in situ experiments performed at Paineira beamline.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Installation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/installation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installation" /><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/installation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/installation/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>
<h1 id="linux">Linux</h1>
<p>When using Linux, you can download Iguape via pip, with the console command:</p>
<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>pip <span class="nb">install </span>iguape
iguape <span class="c">#this will open the software, once it's installed</span>
</code></pre></div></div>
<h1 id="windows">Windows</h1>
<p>For Windows, a instaler can be found in the following link: <a href="https://github.com/cnpem/iguape/releases/download/v1.0.3/Iguape_Installer.exe">Windows Installer</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Installation Linux When using Linux, you can download Iguape via pip, with the console command: pip install iguape iguape #this will open the software, once it's installed Windows For Windows, a instaler can be found in the following link: Windows Installer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/tutorial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorial" /><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/tutorial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web-site-docs/tutorial/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="visuals">Visuals</h2>
<p>The GUI has two tabs and concentrate its features in a button panel at the bottom of the window. The XRD Data tab displays the diffraction patterns stacked by a user-defined offset. The Peak Fitting tab displays the data obtained through peak fitting of the XRD patterns on the selected 2theta interval.
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/fffae287-6076-495d-a3fe-dc6e4289b7c0" alt="Iguape_XRD_Data_Main_Window" />
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4c7c9224-88ac-41ad-bcb7-c248986fdfb3" alt="Iguape_Peak_Fit_PsdVoigt" /></p>
<h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>
<h1 id="initialization"><strong>Initialization</strong></h1>
<p>The first step, once Iguape is initialized, is to select a folder to monitor. This can be done by clicking in the <strong>Folder</strong> option at the upper right corner of the window. It’s important that the selected folder contains the <strong>iguape_fileslist.txt</strong> file. It is though this text document, that Iguape can read the XRD data available at the Folder. 
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/01f48445-52b8-4c89-afb8-43136d05c2d8" alt="Initialization" />
<strong>OBS:</strong> When using Windows, the contents inside the selected folder may not appear when in the file explorer for choosing the desired folder. This is just a visual bug of the interface. If the folder has the desired files (including the iguape_fileslist.txt), the program will work just fine.</p>
<h1 id="custom-vizualization"><strong>Custom Vizualization</strong></h1>
<p>Iguape offers tools for custom visualization of the XRD patterns. These include: XRD patterns offset, 2theta and temperature/measure order masks, zoom, pan and figure saving.
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/785404f5-761b-444a-9f41-3b601b62aaa8" alt="Iguape_tools" />
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/5d5267a4-516c-45af-b2d4-3173848b98b0" alt="Iguape_tools#2" /></p>

<h1 id="peak-fit"><strong>Peak Fit</strong></h1>
<p>Peak fitting is available in Iguape, helping the analysis of sample evotution during <em>in situ</em> experiments. When the Peak Fit button is pressed, a new window will be opened. The user, then, can configure the fitting model and have a preview of the best fit achieved by Iguape.<br />
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3bedf4d9-e06d-4b84-a5a0-9cecd292adbd" alt="PeakFIt" />
<img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/38ef0b40-ea7d-436d-a140-c3b40f8ac19b" alt="Iguape_Peak_Fit_Window_2xPsdVoigt" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visuals The GUI has two tabs and concentrate its features in a button panel at the bottom of the window. The XRD Data tab displays the diffraction patterns stacked by a user-defined offset. The Peak Fitting tab displays the data obtained through peak fitting of the XRD patterns on the selected 2theta interval. Usage Initialization The first step, once Iguape is initialized, is to select a folder to monitor. This can be done by clicking in the Folder option at the upper right corner of the window. It’s important that the selected folder contains the iguape_fileslist.txt file. It is though this text document, that Iguape can read the XRD data available at the Folder. OBS: When using Windows, the contents inside the selected folder may not appear when in the file explorer for choosing the desired folder. This is just a visual bug of the interface. If the folder has the desired files (including the iguape_fileslist.txt), the program will work just fine. Custom Vizualization Iguape offers tools for custom visualization of the XRD patterns. These include: XRD patterns offset, 2theta and temperature/measure order masks, zoom, pan and figure saving.]]></summary></entry></feed>